Hi this is Brenda and today we are working on our pop-up cards.
Project today will be a snowman.
We will need our 5 x 8 index cards, some glitter, glue, markers, scissors and we are ready to begin.
We need to fold our 5 x 8 index card in half like this and we will also have a under liner.
It is also a 5 x 8.
It can be any color that you like and it will be covering up our cuttings that we are going to be making on our index cards.
First we will take our marker; any color that you like.
Just going to draw a simple little snowman; two little circles, a little hat like this, some eyes, a little nose and we will be cutting him out.
For times sake, I am going to show you the finished product like this.
Here’s our little snowman.
The secret to this project is when you are drawing on the snowman you need to make some little tabs on his arms like this and those little tabs are what you are going to glue to the card stock and that is going to be holding him down to the card stock.
You will notice that he’s got a fold also up this half like this so that when you fold it over, he will pop out at you.
This is what it looks like from the side angle.
So those little tabs if you can see underneath are just glued to the index card like this and folded in so that you can’t really see them but they hold him into the card.
I’ve added some glitter to look like snow.
I’ve embellished it with a few little snowflakes.
You can use different colors if you like.
We use our under liner like this to cover up any cuttings so that you can’t see where you cut into the snowman so that when our recipient opens the card like this, the snowman will pop out at him like this.